

# **PROFILE**

I am a doer who has succeeded in fast-paced office environment working as a recruiting consultant for five years. I successfully delivered numerous recruiting projects including at least five senior level (director and above) positions across the APAC region.

I am a quick learner who has excelled in studies of finance and economics with all A's (only three A-'s). I am capable of replicating my prior success in finance professions.

I am a problem solver who is passionate about using analytical approaches to inform financial, investment and other decisions, reflected both in my prior job accomplishments and academic excellence.

I am a challenge seeker who is highly adaptive as echoed in my cross cultural background. I know how to build relationships to effectively negotiate deals.

# **LANGUAGE**

Bilingual in English and Chinese

# **HOBBIES**



Skiing enthusiast



Travel fanatic



Reading nerd



Caffeine addict

# **ERIC ZHILI LIU**

Aspiring Finance Professional

PHONE: +1 (347) 653-5638 WEBSITE: zhili-liu.com

EMAIL: norbitay@hotmail.com

## **EDUCATION**

Baruch College, CUNY

Finance, Minor: Economics | BBA | GPA: 3.9

BMCC, CUNY

Business Management | GPA: 4.0

Shanghai Jiao Tong University

Human Resources Management

08/2021 – 05/2023

08/2019 – 05/2021

09/2010 – 06/2013

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

 Trove-Global Human Resources Consulting Co., Ltd
 09/2015 – 10/2020

 Freelancing Recruiting Consultant
 07/2017 – 10/2020

 Co-founder
 09/2015 – 06/2017

- Coordinated with my co-founder to layout business strategies and successfully developed more than ten accounts from 2015 to 2017.
- Diversified recruiting channels and successfully filled three director positions for MNCs from 2016 to 2017.

# Asia Society Global Talent Initiatives Intern

- Co-hosted three ERG roundtables with HR mangers from MNCs' NYC offices.
- Generated multiple corporate leads for the AAPI workforce survey.

# Kenexa Recruiting Consultant

09/2017 - 03/2018

03/2013 - 09/2015

• Filled at least two mid-level positions within the initial three month period and repeatedly ranked as top quarterly performer.

# **VOLUNTEER**

Shanghai Pride

2012/04 - 2015/06

#### **SKILLS**

**Investment Analysis** 

Financial Econometrics

**Corporate Finance** 

**Technical Analysis** 

**Economic Analysis** 

Microsoft 365 (Office)